She PRP O
tells VBZ O
me PRP O
every DT O
day NN O
at IN O
7am CD B-DATE
and CC O
10pm CD B-DATE
. . O

Let NNP O
us PRP O
meet VBP O
tomorrow NN B-DATE
at IN I-DATE
6pm CD I-DATE
. . O

Let NNP O
us PRP O
go VBP O
today NN B-DATE
at IN I-DATE
3pm CD I-DATE
. . O

Let NNP O
us PRP O
meet VBP O
tomorrow NN B-DATE
at IN I-DATE
2pm CD I-DATE
. . O

Shall NNP O
we PRP O
go VBP O
at IN O
5:00pm CD B-DATE
? . O

I PRP O
went VBD O
to TO O
the DT O
store NN O
this DT B-DATE
morning NN I-DATE
. . O

Early RB B-DATE
last JJ I-DATE
night NN I-DATE
I PRP O
went VBD O
to TO O
the DT O
building NN O
. . O

20 CD B-TEMPORAL
years NNS I-TEMPORAL
before IN O
two CD B-TEMPORAL
hours NNS I-TEMPORAL
ago RB I-TEMPORAL
. . O

What WP O
is VBZ O
now RB O
China NNP B-GPE
was VBD O
inhabited VBN O
by IN O
Homo NNP O
erectus NN O
more JJR B-TEMPORAL
than IN I-TEMPORAL
a DT I-TEMPORAL
million NN I-TEMPORAL
years NNS I-TEMPORAL
ago IN I-TEMPORAL
. . O

Recent JJ O
study NN O
shows VBZ O
that IN O
the DT O
stone NN O
tools NNS O
found VBD O
at IN O
Xiaochangliang NNP B-LOC
site NN O
are VBP O
magnetostratigraphically RB O
dated VBN O
to TO O
1.36 CD B-TEMPORAL
million CD I-TEMPORAL
years NNS I-TEMPORAL
ago IN I-TEMPORAL
. . O

The DT O
archaeological JJ O
site NN O
of IN O
Xihoudu NNP B-LOC
in IN O
Shanxi NNP B-LOC
Province NNP I-LOC
is VBZ O
the DT O
earliest JJS O
recorded VBN O
use NN O
of IN O
fire NN O
by IN O
Homo NNP O
erectus NN O
, , O
which WDT O
is VBZ O
dated VBN O
1.27 CD B-TEMPORAL
million CD I-TEMPORAL
years NNS I-TEMPORAL
ago IN I-TEMPORAL
. . O

The DT O
excavations NNS O
at IN O
Yuanmou NNP B-LOC
and CC O
later JJ O
Lantian NNP B-LOC
show NN O
early RB O
habitation NN O
. . O

Perhaps RB O
the DT O
most RBS O
famous JJ O
specimen NNS O
of IN O
Homo NNP O
erectus NN O
found VBD O
in IN O
China NNP B-GPE
is VBZ O
the DT O
so-called JJ O
Peking NNP B-PER
Man NNP I-PER
discovered VBD O
in IN O
1923-27 CD B-DATE
. . O

The DT O
Neolithic NNP O
age NN O
in IN O
China NNP B-GPE
can MD O
be VB O
traced VBN O
back RP O
to TO O
about IN O
10,000 CD B-DATE
BC NNP I-DATE
. . O

Early RB O
evidence NN O
for IN O
proto-Chinese JJ B-GPE
millet NN O
agriculture NN O
is VBZ O
radiocarbon-dated JJ O
to TO O
about IN O
7000 CD B-DATE
BC NNP I-DATE
. . O

Farming VBG O
gave VBD O
rise NN O
to TO O
the DT O
Jiahu NNP B-GPE
culture NN O
7000 CD B-DATE
to TO I-DATE
5800 CD I-DATE
BC NNP I-DATE
. . O

`` `` O
These DT O
pictographs NNS O
are VBP O
reputed VBN O
to TO O
be VB O
similar JJ O
to TO O
the DT O
earliest JJS O
characters NNS O
confirmed VBD O
to TO O
be VB O
written VBN O
Chinese JJ B-GPE
. . O

Excavation NN O
of IN O
a DT O
Peiligang NNP O
culture NN O
site NN O
in IN O
Xinzheng NNP B-GPE
county NN O
, , O
Henan NNP O
, , O
found VBD O
a DT O
community NN O
that WDT O
flourished VBD O
in IN B-DATE
5,500-4,900 CD I-DATE
BC NNP I-DATE
, , O
with IN O
evidence NN O
of IN O
agriculture NN O
, , O
constructed VBD O
buildings NNS O
, , O
pottery JJ O
, , O
and CC O
burial JJ O
of IN O
the DT O
dead JJ O
. . O

With IN O
agriculture NN O
came VBD O
increased VBN O
population NN O
, , O
the DT O
ability NN O
to TO O
store VB O
and CC O
redistribute VB O
crops NNS O
, , O
and CC O
the DT O
potential JJ O
to TO O
support VB O
specialist NN O
craftsmen NNS O
and CC O
administrators NNS O
. . O

In IN O
late JJ B-DATE
Neolithic NNP I-DATE
times NNS I-DATE
, , O
the DT O
Yellow NNP B-LOC
River NNP I-LOC
valley NN O
began VBD O
to TO O
establish VB O
itself PRP O
as IN O
a DT O
center NN O
of IN O
Yangshao NNP B-GPE
culture NN O
5000 CD B-DATE
BC NNP I-DATE
to TO I-DATE
3000 CD I-DATE
BC NNP I-DATE
, , O
and CC O
the DT O
first JJ O
villages NNS O
were VBD O
founded VBN O
; : O
the DT O
most RBS O
archaeologically RB O
significant JJ O
of IN O
these DT O
was VBD O
found VBN O
at IN O
Banpo NNP B-LOC
, , I-LOC
Xi'an JJ I-LOC
. . O

Later JJ O
, , O
Yangshao NNP O
culture NN O
was VBD O
superseded VBN O
by IN O
the DT O
Longshan NNP O
culture NN O
, , O
which WDT O
was VBD O
also RB O
centered VBN O
on IN O
the DT O
Yellow NNP O
River NNP O
from IN O
about IN O
3000 CD B-DATE
BC NNP I-DATE
to TO I-DATE
2000 CD I-DATE
BC NNP I-DATE
. . O

The DT O
early JJ O
history NN O
of IN O
China NNP B-GPE
is VBZ O
obscured VBN O
by IN O
the DT O
lack NN O
of IN O
written VBN O
documents NNS O
from IN O
this DT O
period NN O
, , O
coupled VBN O
with IN O
the DT O
existence NN O
of IN O
later JJ O
accounts NNS O
that WDT O
attempted VBN O
to TO O
describe VB O
events NNS O
that WDT O
had VBD O
occurred VBN O
several JJ O
centuries NNS O
previously RB O
. . O

In IN O
a DT O
sense NN O
, , O
the DT O
problem NN O
stems NNS O
from IN O
centuries NNS O
of IN O
introspection NN O
on IN O
the DT O
part NN O
of IN O
the DT O
Chinese NNP O
people NNS O
, , O
which WDT O
has VBZ O
blurred VBN O
the DT O
distinction NN O
between IN O
fact NN O
and CC O
fiction NN O
in IN O
regards NNS O
to TO O
this DT O
early JJ O
history NN O
. . O

February NNP B-DATE
29 CD I-DATE
, , I-DATE
2012 CD I-DATE
. . O

March NNP B-DATE
. . O

April NNP B-DATE
. . O

May NNP B-DATE
. . O

July RB B-DATE
. . O

August NNP B-DATE
. . O

September NNP B-DATE
. . O

October NNP B-DATE
. . O

Novmber NNP B-DATE
. . O

December NNP B-DATE
. . O

Summer NNP B-DATE
2011 CD I-DATE
. . O

Winter NNP B-DATE
1999 CD I-DATE
. . O

Spring VBG B-DATE
1323 CD I-DATE
. . O

Wednesday NNP B-DATE
, , I-DATE
February NNP I-DATE
29 CD I-DATE
, , O
2012 CD I-DATE
, , O
at IN I-DATE
4:30pm CD I-DATE
PST NNP I-DATE
. . O

in IN O
the DT O
early JJ B-DATE
1950s CD I-DATE
. . O

September NNP B-DATE
1 CD I-DATE
, , I-DATE
1939 CD I-DATE
- : I-DATE
May NNP I-DATE
8 CD I-DATE
, , I-DATE
1945 CD I-DATE
. . O

December NNP B-DATE
12 CD I-DATE
, , I-DATE
1822 CD I-DATE
to TO I-DATE
March NNP I-DATE
1 CD I-DATE
, , I-DATE
1977 CD I-DATE
. . O

America NNP B-GPE
was VBD O
discovered VBN O
several JJ B-TEMPORAL
hundred CD I-TEMPORAL
years NNS I-TEMPORAL
ago RB I-TEMPORAL
. . O

winter NN B-DATE
2011-2012 CD I-DATE
. . O

He PRP O
worked VBD O
for IN O
two CD B-TEMPORAL
hours NNS I-TEMPORAL
. . O

In IN O
the DT O
1974 CD B-DATE
soccer NN O
World NNP B-GPE
Cup NNP I-GPE
final JJ O
, , O
Germany NNP B-GPE
beat NN O
the DT O
Netherlands NNP B-GPE
2-1 CD O
. . O

The DT O
dollar NN O
traded VBN O
at IN O
0.8012 CD O
Euros NNP O
, , O
up RB O
from IN O
0.7943 CD O
Euros NNP O
on IN O
Monday NNP B-DATE
. . O

A DT O
special JJ O
gubernatorial JJ O
election NN O
will MD O
take VB O
place NN O
next IN B-DATE
Tuesday NNP I-DATE
. . O

this DT O
Wednesday NNP B-DATE
afternoon NN I-DATE
. . O

The DT O
symptoms NNS O
showed VBD O
up RP O
decades NNS B-TEMPORAL
later JJ O
. . O

He PRP O
is VBZ O
likely JJ O
to TO O
serve VB O
on IN O
the DT O
court NN O
for IN O
several JJ B-TEMPORAL
decades NNS I-TEMPORAL
. . O

He PRP O
retired VBD O
years NNS B-TEMPORAL
ago IN I-TEMPORAL
. . O

He PRP O
retired VBD O
more JJR B-TEMPORAL
than IN I-TEMPORAL
five CD I-TEMPORAL
years NNS I-TEMPORAL
ago RB I-TEMPORAL
. . O

The DT O
performance NN O
will MD O
take VB O
between IN B-TEMPORAL
45 CD I-TEMPORAL
minutes NNS I-TEMPORAL
and CC I-TEMPORAL
an DT I-TEMPORAL
hour NN I-TEMPORAL
. . O

Xinhua NNP B-GPE
News NNP I-GPE
Agency NNP I-GPE
, , O
Shanghai NNP I-GPE
, , O
February NNP B-DATE
10 CD B-DATE
, , O
by IN O
wire NN O
reporters NNS O
Jinhu NNP B-PER
Xie NNP I-PER
and CC O
Chijian NNP B-PER
Zhang NNP I-PER
. . O

He PRP O
had VBD O
to TO O
wait VB O
as IN O
long RB B-TEMPORAL
as IN I-TEMPORAL
ten VBN I-TEMPORAL
years NNS I-TEMPORAL
. . O

as IN O
long RB O
as IN O
several JJ B-TEMPORAL
decades NNS I-TEMPORAL
. . O

only RB O
10 CD I-TEMPORAL
minutes NNS I-TEMPORAL
. . O

Our PRP$ O
next JJ O
meeting NN O
will MD O
be VB O
on IN O
Friday NNP B-DATE
at IN I-DATE
11am CD O
. . O

Caesar NNP O
was VBD O
murdered VBN O
in IN O
44 CD O
BC NNP O
. . O

Three CD O
Roman NNP O
legions NNS O
were VBD O
annihilated VBN O
in IN O
the DT O
Battle NNP O
of IN O
the DT O
Teutoburg NNP O
Forest NNP O
in IN O
9 CD O
AD NNP O
. . O

The DT O
9.3 CD O
Tohoku NNP O
earthquake NN O
occured VBD O
in IN O
the DT O
year NN O
Heisei NNP O
23. NNP O
academic JJ O
year NN O
2011-2012 CD O
. . O

United NNP O
States NNPS O
government NN O
fiscal JJ O
year NN O
2012 CD O
. . O

The DT O
Bolshevik NNP O
revolution NN O
started VBD O
on IN B-DATE
October NNP I-DATE
25 CD I-DATE
, , I-DATE
1917 CD I-DATE
. . O

The DT O
Bolshevik NNP B-GPE
revolution NN O
started VBD O
on IN B-DATE
Novmber NNP I-DATE
7 CD I-DATE
, , I-DATE
1917. CD I-DATE
eight CD I-DATE
o'clock JJ I-DATE
in IN I-DATE
the DT I-DATE
morning NN I-DATE
local JJ I-DATE
time NN I-DATE
. . O

10am CD B-DATE
California NNP I-DATE
time NN I-DATE
. . O

10:00 CD B-DATE
UTC NNP B-DATE
. . O

Augustus NNP O
lived VBD O
from IN B-DATE
63 CD I-DATE
BCE NNP I-DATE
to TO I-DATE
14 CD I-DATE
CE NNP I-DATE
. . O

Patrick NNP B-PER
Makau NNP I-PER
finished VBD O
the DT O
marathon NN O
in IN O
2 CD B-TEMPORAL
hours NNS I-TEMPORAL
, , I-TEMPORAL
3 CD I-TEMPORAL
minutes NNS I-TEMPORAL
and CC I-TEMPORAL
38 CD I-TEMPORAL
seconds NNS I-TEMPORAL
. . O

The DT O
poet NN O
William NNP B-PER
Shakespeare NNP I-PER
was VBD O
born VBN O
in IN O
Stratford-upon-Avon NNP B-LOC
on IN O
April NNP B-DATE
23 CD B-DATE
, , O
1564. CD O
our PRP$ O
first JJ O
visit NN O
in IN O
10 CD B-TEMPORAL
years NNS B-TEMPORAL
. . O

They PRP O
lobbied VBD O
Congress NNP B-GPE
to TO O
repeal VB O
the DT O
15-year-old JJ O
law NN O
. . O

When WRB O
I PRP O
met VBP O
her PRP O
for IN O
the DT O
first JJ O
time NN O
, , O
Mary NNP B-PER
still RB O
worked VBD O
for IN O
Goldman NNP B-GPE
Sachs NNP I-GPE
. . O

every DT B-TEMPORAL
other JJ I-TEMPORAL
week NN I-TEMPORAL
. . O

every DT B-DATE
other JJ I-DATE
Wednesday NNP I-DATE
. . O

He PRP O
earns VBZ O
$ $ O
42,000 CD O
per IN O
year NN B-TEMPORAL
. . O

We PRP O
play VBP O
bridge NN O
every DT O
Wednesday NNP B-DATE
afternoon NN B-DATE
. . O

He PRP O
calls VBZ O
me PRP O
every DT O
day NN O
at IN O
8am CD B-DATE
and CC O
5pm CD B-DATE
. . O
